Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello
1973-1994
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.006
59 Linear Feet (57 boxes)
George Bugliarello was a visionary engineer, educator and administrator who was instrumental in reviving Polytechnic after its financial crisis in the early 1970s as well as developing a MetroTech Center, a university-industry park in downtown Brooklyn. The Presidential papers of George Bugliarello contain administrative and personal correspondence, memoranda, reports, publications, clippings produced by George Bugliarello, 13th President of then Polytechnic Institute of New York, during his tenure as President of Polytechnic University between 1973 and 1994.
Biographical Note
On October 15, 1973, George Bugliarello was inaugurated 13th President of what was then known as the Polytechnic Institute of New York. President Bugliarello took the reins at the most precarious time in Polytechnic's long history. Amid a national economic crisis in the 1970s, several private academic institutions in New York City were on the brink of collapse, including Polytechnic and New York University. On the brink of bankruptcy, New York University was forced to sell its University Heights campus in the Bronx to the City of New York. New York University also lost its School of Engineering in a merger with Polytechnic University of Brooklyn, which was then renamed Polytechnic University of New York. George Bugliarello, who served as President for between 1973 and 1994 and subsequently served as President emeritus and Chancellor until 2011, proved to be lucky Number 13 for the Institute and for the struggling neighborhood of Downtown Brooklyn.
Giorgio Bugliarello was born Georgio Bugliarello-Wondrich on May 20, 1927 to Spera Bugliarello-Wondrich and Colonel Federico Bugliarello Magnano di San Lio in Trieste, Italy. He graduated summa cum laude from the University of Padua where he earned a Dottore in Ingegneria (Dott.Ing.) in Civil Engineering. In 1954 he earned a Master's in Civil Engineering from the University of Minnesota on a Fulbright Scholarship. He then attended Massachusetts Institute of Technology's School of Engineering from 1956-1959, earning a doctorate in Civil Engineering and Hydronamics. George Bugliarello married his wife of over 50 years, Virginia Harding, in 1959. The couple had two sons, Nicholas and David.
Bugliarello taught Civil Engineering, Biotechnology and Bio-Engineering at Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) between 1959 and 1969, serving as founding directory of the Bio-Engineering program at CMU in 1964. In 1969, Bugliarello was appointed Dean of Engineering and Professor of Civil Engineering and Biotechnology at University of Illinois at Chicago Circle.
Despite a large deficit and bitterness and confusion among students and faculty of NYU's School of Engineering and Polytechnic Institute during the merger, Bugliarello made it his mission to revive Polytechnic by focusing on three goals: Increasing enrollment and academic programs through satellite campuses in Westchester and Long Island, increasing fundraising efforts and alumni outreach and develop a technological-industrial park in downtown Brooklyn. George Bugliarello was instrumental in the development of the MetroTech Center in Downtown Brooklyn which currently houses the NYU-Polytechnic campus. Bugliarello's success in combining academic, scientific and public development during his career was immortalized in the term he coined "Biosoma", a contraction of biology, society and machines. It's therefore unsurprising to learn that Bugliarello was instrumental in designing the seal of Polytechnic University – Homo Et Homines Opera Partes Naturae: Man and the works of man belong to nature.
George Bugliarello's professional and academic involvements and achievements are almost innumerable. Bugliarello served as member and chair of American Society of Civil Engineers, American Society of Engineering Education, National Academy of Engineering, National Academy of Sciences, National Science Foundation, New York City Mayor's Commission on Science and Technology, and many others. Highlights include serving as founder and editor of the journal Technology in Society, president of Sigma Xi Scientific Research Society, founding fellow of the American Institute for Medical and Biological Engineering, fellow of dozens of scientific, academic and business societies, and receiving eight honorary degrees. Over his lifetime, Bugliarello published 17 books, over 350 articles, reports, and editorials and 18 newspaper articles. George Bugliarello died on February 18, 2011 in Port Washington, New York at the age of 83.
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into eight series.
Additional materials were donated to the Poly Archives by Virigina Bugliarello in 2013. These items were integrated into the original collection and created some irregularities in box numbering (i.e. Box 44.1).
This collection has been organized into eleven series:
Arrangement
Subject Files
Bern Dibner Library / CATT
Polytechnic
Organizations
Speeches & Symposiums
Publications and Manuscripts
Correspondence
Clippings
Photographs
Early Career
Addendum
Addendum II
Provenance
The Administrative Papers of President George Bugliarello were deposited at the Polytechnic Institute of New York University in 1995 following Geroge Bugliarello's stepping-down as President and transitioning to his position as Chancellor and President emeritus. The records in this collection were created and collected by George Bugliarello and his office staff in the President's Office.
Related Archival Material at Polytechnic Institute of New York University
RG.7: Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello, 1994-2011
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection that contain sensitive and personal information have been restricted from view. Folders containing restricted material have been marked and will be separated from the collection prior to use by researchers.
Scope and Content Note
This collection documents the activities of George Bugliarello, who was 13th President of Polytechnic Institute of New York between 1973 and 1994. The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, financial records, published and unpublished writings, clippings, architectural floor plans, photographs, research notes and bound appointment books pertaining to the professional, scientific and academic activities of President George Bugliarello. The records in this collection highlight the extent of George Bugliarello's professional involvement in a wide array of scientific, academic and public organizations, committees and conferences. The bulk of the collection falls within the span of George Bugliarello's presidency (1973-1994), however the dates in this collection span from 1952 to 1997.
Sponsor note
This project was made possible by a generous grant from Violet J. Jacobs and the Jacobs Family Trust.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Virginia Bugliarello in 2011.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Administrative records; Pamphlets; Memoranda; Articles; Speeches; Clippings; Minutes; Correspondence; Gramercy Park (New York, N.Y.); Long Island, N.Y.; Engineering; Photographs; Research notes; Publications; Biosoma; Business cards; Trieste (Italy); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Monographs; Westchester County (N.Y.)
- Series I: Subject Files
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains original subject files from the President's office and contains correspondence, memoranda, reports and minutes.
  Arrangement Note
  The majority of the folders in this series are ordered alphabetically according to the original folder titles. Documents pertaining to the development of MetroTech Center and George Bugliarello's involvement in the Gramercy Park steam pipe explosion investigation have been separated into separate subseries based on the volume of documents on the topic.
  - Subseries A: Alphabetical Files
    - Advisory Committee on Technology and Innovation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alumni Statistics, 1987 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AAAS, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AAAS, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - AAAS - Annual Meeting, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - AAAS - Annual Meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - AAAS - Meeting - Mexico City, 1973 July 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - AAAS - Subcommittee for Federal Information Management, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - AAAS - Symposium, February 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Arbitration Association, 1983 September-October (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Association for Engineering Societies, 1983 October, 1992 January, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - American Astrological Society, 1975, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - American Electronics Association, 1991 February-June (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - American Society of Chemical Engineering (ASCE) – EMD Advisory Board, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ASCE – EMD Advisory Board, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ASCE – Miscellaneous, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - ASCE – Conferences, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - ASCE – Fellows, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - ASCE – Task Committee on Goals, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - ASCE – Technical Council on Computer Practices, 1973 October-1974 January (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - ASEE – 100th Anniversary, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - ASEE – Annual Conference Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - ASEE - 1981 Conference (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - ASEE – 1993 Conference, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - ASEE – Manuscripts for Knoxville Symposium, 1976-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - ASEE – 1976 Conference, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - ASEE - Colorado Conference, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - ASEE – Conference, 1980 June (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - ASEE – 1977 Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1996, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Angelini, Arnaldo, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Angermueller, Hans, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Polytechnic - Annual Report, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Polytechnic - Annual Meeting Minutes, 1989 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Polytechnic - Advisory Committee, 1989 March (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Annual Report, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report, 1988 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report, 1989 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Analytic Services (ANSER), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Asheville, North Carolina - Trip Itinerary, 1993 November (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ausubel, Jesse H., 1995 January-February (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Board of Engineering Education – Transparencies – NSPE Louisville, 1995 July (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Ben Yen – Hong Kong, 1996 January-February (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Berenback, Steve B., 1996 April-June (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bio Flows – GB Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bio Flows – GB Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bio Flows – Figures and Graphics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bio Flows – Correspondence, Articles, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bio Flows – Chapter 1 Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bio Flows – Chapter 2-3 Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bio Flows – Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bio Flows – Articles, Research, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bio Flows – Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bio Flows - Notes, Outlines, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Biosoma – Research Articles, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Board – Committee to Advise the President on Fostering Growth, 1984 January (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Board – Revision, Membership Pages, 1989 June (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Board – Management Committee, 1990 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Board – Poly Corporation, 1994 June (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Board – Welcome Letters to New Trustees, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Board Meetings – GB Handwritten Note, 1985? (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Board Meeting – Executive Committee, 1989 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Board Meetings, 1989 March 16, June 5 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Board Meeting, 1989 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Board Meeting – Poly Fellows, 1989 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Board on Science and Technology in International Development (BOSTID) – News, 1981 March (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bourass, Mohammed, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Borodavchenko, Evgeny – Recommendation, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Branscomb, Anne, 1979 July 31-August 1 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Brewer, Curtis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Budget Inquiries - RESTRICT, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bugliarello – Curriculum vitae, 1987 June-1993 June (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Bugliarello – Biography, 1988 January-1993 February (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bugliarello – Bibliography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Bugliarello – Christmas Card Lists, 1988, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Bugliarello – Personal, 1973-1992, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Bugliarello – Peter Glaser, Arthur D. Little, Inc. – Solar Power, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bugliarello – Poly Press Release, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bugliarello – Professional Organization Registration, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bugliarello – Copy of Naturalization for University of Minnesota, 1954, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bugliarello – Lord Corporation Security Clearance - RESTRICT, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bugliarello – Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bulkin, Professor Bernard, 1974-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bumas, Lester O., 1976-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bussard, Ellen, 1996 March-October (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Burkart, Joseph, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bush, Alfred, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bylaws – With notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bylaws – Faculty, 1990 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Calarco, Vincent, 1988 November (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - California Alumni, 1990 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - California Trip, 1986 October (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - California Trip, 1987 May (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - California Trip – Dinner, 1988 March (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - California Trip, 1989 June (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - California Trip - San Francisco, 1989 August 29-31 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - California Trip, 1990 June (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - California Trip, 1991 June (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Canavaciol, Frank, 1987 November (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Carey, Gov. Hugh L., 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Casazzone, Ralph W., 1993 June (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cassidy, Gerald, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Cassidy, Gerald, 1986-1989, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Universita Di Catania, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Catell, Robert B., 1992 February-April (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - People's Republic of China, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Chitester, Robert J., 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Choudhury Deo C. Professor, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Chung Kung Mo, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Clippings – Polytechnic University, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Code of Practice – Polytechnic University, 1968 January (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Coler, Myron A Dr., 1975-1977, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Colwell, Dr. Rita R., 1995 March-April (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Commencement, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Commission on Independent Colleges and Universities (CICU), 1994 September-1995 June (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - CICU, 1995 August-1996 September (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Computers, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Corporation - Committee Assignments, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Confino, Barbara, 1996 May (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Conklin, David, 1988 July-September (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Cooper, Marc S., 1995 April-August (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Copley, A.L. Dr., 1974-1992, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Corey, Dr. Michael R., 1993 June (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Cost of Things, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Council of Scientific Society Presidents (CCSP), 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Coughlin, Patrick, 1991 November-December (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Cox, Donald M., 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Culliton, Barbara, 1984 March-1985 August (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Cullman, Lewis, 1989 August-1990 March (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Cuomo, Mario Gov. – 1988 Distinguished Service Award, 1987 November - 1990 July (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Damadian, Dr. Raymond, 1989 June (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - DeCarlo, Charles, 1992 April (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - DeSio, Robert W. – IBM, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Poly Development Committee Meetings, 1989 January-May (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Poly Development – Fundraising Prospects – CONFIDENTIAL, 1989 February-May (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Polytechnic - Development – ASME Meeting Chicago - November 27-December 2, 1988, 1988 January-December (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Chairman Search Committee, 1986 May-July (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Committee Meeting, 1988 November 16 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Committee Meeting, 1988 December 7 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Strategic Planning – Long Island & Westchester Campus, 1988 December-1992 May (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Strategic Planning – Long Island Campus (VHS), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Strategic Planning – MetroTech, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Polytechnic - Development – Strategic Planning – Westinghouse Site, 1991 October-1993 April (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dibner, Bern, 1978 April-1988 October (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dichter, Ernst, 1980 July (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Donaruma, Dr. L. Guy, 1981 July-1985 June (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Dow Chemical Company Foundation, 1987 February-1990 May (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dowell, Earl H., 1984 September-1990 February (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Dressner, Ellen E., 1987 February-1990 October (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Dropkin, John J., 1976 October-1989 June (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Drori, Ze'ev, 1987 June-1990 March (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Drucker, Daniel C., 1988 July-1989 April (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Dubos, Dr. Rene, 1975 February-March (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Dubow, Joel, 1990 December-1992 January (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Dubridge, Lee A., 1974 March-October (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Duchin, Dr. Faye, 1988 April-1990 February (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Duchting, Professor Dr. Ing. Werner, 1989 June-December (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Dulaney, Peggy – Rockefeller Foundation, 1981 August-1989 September (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - DuPont DeNemours & Co., 1974 November-1988 June (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - D'Arcangelo, Mark J. – Synergos Institute, 1988 January (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Doc – Dre – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1978-1990 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Dri-Dru – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1977-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Duc-Dut – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Eaton Corporation, 1987 March-1988 November (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - EBASCO Services Inc., 1976 April-1979 June (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - The Economic Club of New York, 1988-1990 November (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Education Committee for Foreign Medical Graduates (ECFMG), 1986 December-1994 October (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Education Committee for Foreign Medical Graduates (ECFMG), 1995 January-1997 January, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Educational Technology, 1976 August (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Egypt – Applied Scientific & Technology Research Program – Assessment, Volume 1, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Egypt – Applied Scientific & Technology Research Program – Joint Consultative Committee, 1978 May 6-9 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Egypt – Applied Scientific & Technology Research Program – Joint Consultative Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Egypt – Board of Science and Technology for International Development, 1977 March-1983 November (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Egypt – BOSTID – Panel Report, 1982 August 27 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Ehrenhalt, Samuel M., 1988 January-1990 February (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Albert Einstein Chair in Science, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Eirich, Frederick, 1967 April-1979 December (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Eirich, Frederick, 1980 December-1989 September (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Eirich, Frederick, 1980-1992 April, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Eisenberg, Anne, 1988 October-1990 May (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Electric Power Research Institute, 1993 February (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Energy Research and Development Authority (ERDA), 1976 July-1980 June (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Engdahl, George E., 1988 July-September (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Engineer & The Historian" by George Bugliarello, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Englund John A., 1988 June-1991 July (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Erbsen, Claude E., 1990 January-March (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Escobar, Carole, 1987 June-1990 April (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Eurich, Nell, 1978 January-1989 February (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Executive Seminars, Polytechnic, 1978 November-1985 October (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Exxon, 1988 May-1990 August (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Eyerman, Edward, 1990 November-December (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Eag-EEOC – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1975-1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Eg-Eig – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Ele-End – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1976-1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Eng-Ent – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1975-1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Epner – Ew – Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Faculty Resolution – Memos to Faculty, 1989 July-1990 January (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Faculty Resolution, 1990 March-September (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Faculty Resolution – Lester Bumas, 1990 March 7-14 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Faculty Resolution – Annual Report 1988-89, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Faculty Resolution – No Confidence Vote – Ballots & Results, 1989 October (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Faculty Resolution – GB Address to Faculty, 1989 September 13 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Faculty Resolution – Faculty Notes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Faculty Resolution– Newspaper Articles / Press Re. President's Salary, 1989 October-November (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Faculty Resolution –Responses to Resolution, 1989 September-November (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Faculty Resolution – Response to Faculty, 1989 July 31 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Faculty Resolution – Faculty Trustee Responses for George Bugliarello, 1989 November-July (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Faggin, Dr. Federico, 1990 January-May (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Fanton, Jonathan, 1986 April-1990 January (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Featherman, Dr. David, 1992 July (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Feerst, Irwin, 1977 June-1978 January (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Board of Fellows – Nominees & Members, 1989 March-1990 October (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Fellows Scholarship Fund, 1990 November–May (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Ferguson, William, 1983 December-1989 September (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Fernandez, Joseph, 1989 December-1992 April (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ferraboschi, Paolo, 1992 October-November (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Ferraro, Arnaldo A., 1985 October-1986 January (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Ferro, Lucio, 1988 February-August (Box 5, Folder 44)